<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Commons-rsses on CC Core Certification</title>
    <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Commons-rsses on CC Core Certification</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:40:27 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Commons</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:40:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;creative-commons-core-certificate&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Core Certificate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-commons&#34;&gt;The Commons&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Commons has long played a historical role in making cultural and natural resources accessible to all members of a society.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Significance of the Commons</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/significance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/significance/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;What do Wikipedia and medieval English pasture lands have in common? (Hint: the answer is right there in the question.) And why should you care?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-question&#34;&gt;The Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Wikipedia and medieval English pasture lands are examples of a Commons. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bollier.org/commons-short-and-sweet&#34;&gt;As economist David Bollier describes it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a Commons arises whenever a given community decides it wishes to manage a resource in a collective manner, with special regard for equitable access, use and sustainability”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commons are everywhere - from modern web communities to ancient agrarian communities - and understanding what they are and how they function is key to understanding the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably participate in one or more Commons yourself - and by the time you finish this module you’ll be able to recognize a Commons you are part of, describe what makes it a Commons, and identify potential threats to the sustainability of your Commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/pasture-wikipedia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;quot;English Pasture and Wikipedia logo&#34; title=&#34;English Pasture and Wikipedia logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Composite of &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Plan_mediaeval_manor.jpg&#34;&gt;Fictional Medieval Manor&lt;/a&gt; dervivative Wikimedia Commons image by William R. Shepherd (1923) licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/public_domain&#34;&gt;Public Domain&lt;/a&gt; and   &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Wikipedia_Logo_1.0.png&#34;&gt;Wikipedia Logo 1.0&lt;/a&gt;  Wikimedia Commons image by &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/User:Nohat&#34;&gt;Nohat&lt;/a&gt;  licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define the commons and its historical significance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe historical and ongoing enclosure of the commons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specific threat to the commons via business models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contrast Hardin’s theoretical “Tragedy of the Commons” to Ostrom’s findings on how communities self-govern commons in practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide examples of common resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe and provide examples of public goods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe culture as a form of Commons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate whether something should be in the commons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contrast the closed status quo vs open&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;opening-questions&#34;&gt;Opening Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Commons are you a part of? Can you think of a group you belong to that collectively manages a resource in order to make sure that everyone will have ongoing access to the resource? What do you contribute to your Commons?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-commons&#34;&gt;What is The Commons?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/the-commons.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Commons&#34; title=&#34;The Commons&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geograph.org.uk/photo/1257161&#34;&gt;The Commons Nature Reserve W.G.C&lt;/a&gt; Geograph photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geograph.org.uk/profile/20403&#34;&gt;Paul Shreeve&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt; / cropped from original&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the commons, how the commons works and to understand some of the history of the commons, read and watch the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7bQiBcd7mBc&#34;&gt;How Does The Commons Work?&lt;/a&gt; YouTube video by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7bQiBcd7mBc&#34;&gt;The Next System Project&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we use &amp;ldquo;commoning&amp;rdquo; as a process to transform the social paradigm of our current system? In his paper for our &amp;ldquo;New Systems: Possibilities and Proposals&amp;rdquo; series exploring viable political-economic alternatives to the present order, economist David Bollier suggests we rethink the traditional &amp;ldquo;tragedy of the commons&amp;rdquo; argument, moving instead toward new and innovative ways to equitably manage shared resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7bQiBcd7mBc&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7bQiBcd7mBc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bollier.org/commons-short-and-sweet&#34;&gt;The Commons, Short and Sweet&lt;/a&gt; blog post by &lt;a href=&#34;http://bollier.org/&#34;&gt;David Bollier&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/us/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am always trying to figure out how to explain the idea of the commons to newcomers who find it hard to grasp.  In preparation for a talk that I gave at the Caux Forum for Human Security, near Montreux, Switzerland, I came up with a fairly short overview, which I have copied below.  I think it gets to the nub of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commons is….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A social system for the long-term stewardship of resources that preserves shared values and community identity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A self-organized system by which communities manage resources (both depletable and and replenishable) with minimal or no reliance on the Market or State.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wealth that we inherit or create together and must pass on, undiminished or enhanced, to our children.  Our collective wealth includes the gifts of nature, civic infrastructure, cultural works and traditions, and knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A sector of the economy (and life!) that generates value in ways that are often taken for granted – and often jeopardized by the Market-State.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bollier.org/commons-short-and-sweet&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=41Dr8Te1OwE&#34;&gt;Define the Commons - David Bollier, USA&lt;/a&gt; YouTube video by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChz4DMZKHYnAPVEjXduVFIA&#34;&gt;Remix The Commons&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A definition of the &amp;ldquo;Commons&amp;rdquo; proposed by David Bollier, a member of the Commons Strategies Group (CSG), taken from an interview conducted by Alain Ambrosi, at the Economics and the Commons Conference  which took place in Berlin from 22 to 24 May 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=41Dr8Te1OwE&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=41Dr8Te1OwE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-the-commons-important&#34;&gt;Why is the Commons Important?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we understand the Commons, let’s talk a little bit about why the commons is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.benkler.org/Upgrade-Novatica%20Commons.pdf&#34;&gt;The Political Economy of Commons&lt;/a&gt; a published paper in UPGRADE (European Journal for the
Informatics Professional) PDF by  &lt;a href=&#34;http://benkler.org&#34;&gt;Yochai Benkler&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why Commons?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commons are institutional spaces, in which we can practice a particular type of freedom – freedom from the constraints we normally accept as necessary preconditions to functional markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Though we often think of ‘free markets’ as spaces that enable free choice, in fact these are structured relationships intended to elicit a particular datum – the comparative willingness and ability of agents to pay money for resource.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most important constraints under-girding markets are those we usually call property. Property is a cluster of background rules that determine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what resources each of us has when we come into relations with others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what ‘having’ or ‘lacking’ a resource allows us to do or refuse to do in relations surrounding resources. These rules impose constraints on who can do what in the domain of actions that require access to resources that are the subjects of property law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;While a necessary precondition for markets, property law means that choice in markets is itself not free of constraints, but is instead constrained in a particular pattern&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commons are institutional spaces where human agents can act free of the particular constraints required for markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This does not mean that commons are anarchic spaces. Purely free action is illusory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It means that individuals and groups can use resources governed under different types of constraints than those imposed by property law. These constraints may be social, or physical, or regulatory. They may make individuals more or less free, in some aggregate sense, than do property rules. Whether a commons in fact enhances freedom or harms it then, depends on how the commons is structured, and on how property rights in the resource would have been structured in the absence of a commons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20130617041302/http://www.boell.org/downloads/Benkler_The_Political_Economy_of_the_Commons.pdf&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-enclosure&#34;&gt;What is Enclosure?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/hedge-enclosure-boundary.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enclosure Boundary&#34; title=&#34;photo of Enclosure Boundary&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geograph.org.uk/photo/1715089&#34;&gt;NZ0314 : Decaying hedge&lt;/a&gt; Geograph photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geograph.org.uk/profile/34816&#34;&gt;Andy Waddington&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt; / cropped from original&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the idea of The Commons, the process of enclosure came too from the history of land ownership in England. Explore it&amp;rsquo;s history and ongoing occurrence from the definition in Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Enclosure&#34;&gt;Enclosure&lt;/a&gt; is a Wikipedia entry licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enclosure (sometimes inclosure) was the legal process in England during the 18th century of enclosing a number of small landholdings to create one larger farm.  Once enclosed, use of the land became restricted to the owner, and it ceased to be common land for communal use. In England and Wales the term is also used for the process that ended the ancient system of arable farming in open fields. Under enclosure, such land is fenced (enclosed) and deeded or entitled to one or more owners. The process of enclosure began to be a widespread feature of the English agricultural landscape during the 16th century. By the 19th century, unenclosed commons had become largely restricted to rough pasture in mountainous areas and to relatively small parts of the lowlands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enclosure could be accomplished by buying the ground rights and all common rights to accomplish exclusive rights of use, which increased the value of the land. The other method was by passing laws causing or forcing enclosure, such as Parliamentary enclosure. The latter process of enclosure was sometimes accompanied by force, resistance, and bloodshed, and remains among the most controversial areas of agricultural and economic history in England. Marxist and neo-Marxist historians argue that rich landowners used their control of state processes to appropriate public land for their private benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Enclosure&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To further understand enclosure as a concept, let’s take a look at the effects of enclosure upon the Commons. Listen to the audio at 5:00-7:47 from David Bollier&amp;rsquo;s podcast &lt;a href=&#34;http://bollier.org/week-4-history-commons-and-enclosure&#34;&gt;Week 4: The History of Commons and Enclosure&lt;/a&gt; for his  &amp;ldquo;The Commons Rising&amp;rdquo; course he taught at Amherst College in the Spring 2010 semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-tragedy-of-the-commons&#34;&gt;The Tragedy of the Commons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/grazing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Grazing&#34; title=&#34;photo of a horse grazing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/pmarkham/3532783271&#34;&gt;Grazing&lt;/a&gt; flickr photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/pmarkham/&#34;&gt;Pete Marhham&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read about the sustainability of the commons under the section 3 &amp;ldquo;Are Commons Sustainable?&amp;rdquo; from Yochai Benkler&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Political Economy of Commons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.benkler.org/Upgrade-Novatica%20Commons.pdf&#34;&gt;The Political Economy of Commons&lt;/a&gt; a published paper in UPGRADE (European Journal for the Informatics Professional) PDF by  &lt;a href=&#34;http://benkler.org&#34;&gt;Yochai Benkler&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt; starting on page 7&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 1960s Garrett Hardin coined an immensely effective trope, &lt;em&gt;“the tragedy of the commons.”&lt;/em&gt; Originally aimed to explain why private incentives would lead to firms to pollute their environment even against their own long term interest, and thereby to justify pollution controls, the trope took on a life of its own. It came to stand for a proposition that all commons are tragic, and that property rights are a necessary precondition to efficient, or even sustainable, resource management. Over the past twenty years or so, we have seen the development of a literature that challenges this now-standard understanding of commons. Most crisply this effort has come to be crystallized in the work of Eleanor Ostrom. A recent review and bibliographic essay by Hess and Ostrom provides an excellent overview of this literature. The crux of most of this work is that there are certain circumstances under which common property regimes are sustainable, and quite possibly more efficient than individual property regimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.benkler.org/Upgrade-Novatica%20Commons.pdf&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While very popular as a phrase, many have criticized &amp;ldquo;the tragedy of the commons&amp;rdquo; most notably Ian Angus, editor of Climate and Capitalism. In 2008 he published &lt;a href=&#34;http://mrzine.monthlyreview.org/2008/angus250808.html&#34;&gt;The Myth of the Tragedy of the Commons&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Monthly Review.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As summarized in  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onthecommons.org/debunking-tragedy-commons&#34;&gt;Debunking the Tragedy of the Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angus notes that Hardin offers no empirical evidence that herders actually overgraze their cattle on shared plots of land, let alone that this is the general rule for shared resources. He also notes that Hardin provides no evidence that private ownership necessarily manages a resource more responsibly; indeed, the “tragedy of the market” is a well-documented phenomenon. Angus also reviews briefly the political usefulness of the tragedy thesis, and its continued misuse in contemporary economics and policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explore Angus&amp;rsquo;s arguments in &lt;a href=&#34;http://mrzine.monthlyreview.org/2008/angus250808.html&#34;&gt;The Myth of the Tragedy of the Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-to-explore&#34;&gt;More to Explore&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wealthofthecommons.org/contents&#34;&gt;The World of the Commons: Beyond Market and State&lt;/a&gt; book edited by &lt;a href=&#34;http://bollier.org/&#34;&gt;David Bollier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://commonsblog.de/&#34;&gt;Silke Helfrich&lt;/a&gt;  licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/us/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.molleindustria.org/en/freeculturegame/&#34;&gt;Free Culture Game&lt;/a&gt; online interactive game (requires Flash) created by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.molleindustria.org/&#34;&gt;Molleindustria&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/deed.en_US&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-quest-taking-on-the-big-question&#34;&gt;Your Quest: Taking on the Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all familiar with the ideas of markets and governments, but we tend to be less familiar with the idea of a Commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, once you understand what a Commons is and how it works you begin to see that they’re all around you - from online communities that develop open source software or open content to face to face communities that manage community gardens or bike co-ops. Commoning is a powerful, proven strategy for coming together to managing resources in a way that ensures that members of the community will continue to have access to the resources - without resorting to the potential abuses of markets and inefficiencies of governments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer by completing this CC Quest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Your Commons?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identify a Commons you participate in and briefly describe the nature of the resources shared in that Commons, some of the people who participate in that Commons, and some of the community’s norms about how to create, manage, and sustain the resources in that Commons. How do you benefit from your participation in that Commons? What do you contribute to that Commons? &lt;a href=&#34;http://quests.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Complete this Quest&lt;/a&gt; (link to be added).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increase your CC Cred by &lt;a href=&#34;http://quests.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;doing additional quests&lt;/a&gt; (link to be added).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CC Opportunity</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/opportunity/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a time in the new future in which all writing can be commercialized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-question&#34;&gt;The Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the magic of a new technology which can automatically capture and upload them to a website, every napkin doodle, every journal entry, and every love letter can be made available for sale as soon as you finish writing them. By means of improvements to operating systems like Windows, Mac, and Linux, all written documents like emails, homework assignments, and office memos can be automatically posted for sale on the site as soon as they are saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An upgrade to the technology might help users automatically offer all images they create for sale, from mobile phone photos to crayon drawings to watercolor paintings. Future versions of the technology might provide the same functionality for videos and sound recordings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/future-scanner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Technology Infographics Computer&#34; title=&#34;graphic of futuristic computer interface&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pixabay.com/en/technology-informatics-computers-298256/&#34;&gt;Technology-298256&lt;/a&gt; Pixabay image by &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixabay.com/en/users/andrelyra-201440/&#34;&gt;andreleya&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/&#34;&gt;CC0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now imagine that when this final version of the software is released, the national government requires all citizens to install it on all their devices, mandating the commercialization of every creative work that will ever be produced in the future, regardless of how trivial - or personal - it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a thousand things wrong with this scenario&lt;/strong&gt;. And while the technology sounds fantastic and distant, the legal foundation of this dystopian future is already in place. After joining the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Berne_Convention&#34;&gt;Berne Convention&lt;/a&gt;, most countries in the world now automatically apply copyright - the legal protections necessary to effectively commercialize a creative work - to each and every creative work the moment it is created, regardless of how personal or trivial it is. In this worldview that anticipates the commercialization of all creative works, a three year old child’s wobbly pencil drawing is protected to the same degree as Star Wars or Harry Potter. And this is not a hypothetical future scenario, it’s the actual state of affairs in the world today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation is utterly preposterous for many reasons, but one important reason is that many people create things with the goal of sharing them with others, like directions for purifying water after a natural disaster. What if a creator doesn’t want their work “protected” from copying and distribution, but wants it copied and shared as far and wide as technologically possible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Return to our imaginary scenario for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if, recognizing the public backlash, a second technology company created a tool that allowed a person to remove things from the website that commercialized all creative work? While it wouldn’t be able to prevent things from being placed on the site for sale automatically (as the law required), it would provide people with an easy - and legal - way to remove things from the site that they didn’t want to commercialize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to the real world, this is essentially what an open license does. Open licenses are easy to use legal tools - copyright licenses - that allow people to choose to share their work with others under a range of conditions. Rather than being forced to accept the default All Rights Reserved “protection” the law automatically forces on each and every creative work, a creator or author can choose to apply an open license license to their work, thereby allowing it to be copied and shared widely and legally. Many open licenses also grant permission to make changes and improvements to the work, like translating the document about purifying water into other languages. By applying an open license to their creation, an author places that work in a broader commons of creative works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/image-placeholder.png&#34; alt=&#34;lead image&#34; title=&#34;Lead Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://image.link&#34;&gt;Image Title&lt;/a&gt; site photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://person.link&#34;&gt;Person Name&lt;/a&gt;  is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons/org/licenselink&#34;&gt;CC-XX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dramatize problem open licensing is solving/addressing, how it is an alternative to copyright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Illustrate where open licensing exists on spectrum between public domain &amp;amp; copyright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain potentials, uses of open licensing, value of sharing as a default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze the reasons for open licensing in your context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define opportunities / benefits of collaborative peer production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate benefits of access to knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;opening-questions&#34;&gt;Opening Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should all writing, images, videos, sound recordings, and other creative works be automatically protected by copyright so they can be commercialized? Think of all the things you create every day - emails, photos, videos, and more. You may have authored a million or more creative works over your lifetime. Even if you are a creative professional and earn your livelihood by selling creative works, over 99.999% of what you have created has rightly gone uncommercialized. What might be the benefit of sharing some of these works with colleagues, peers, other organizations, or “the community”? How might your work be improved upon if you gave others permission to make improvements?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-it&#34;&gt;What is It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/image-placeholder.png&#34; alt=&#34;Nice image&#34; title=&#34;Nice Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://image.link&#34;&gt;Image Title&lt;/a&gt; site photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://person.link&#34;&gt;Person Name&lt;/a&gt;  is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons/org/licenselink&#34;&gt;CC-XX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-section&#34;&gt;Another Section&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we understand it, let’s talk a little bit about why it is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-section-1&#34;&gt;Another Section&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we understand it, let’s talk a little bit about why it is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-section-2&#34;&gt;Another Section&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we understand it, let’s talk a little bit about why it is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-to-explore&#34;&gt;More to Explore&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commons-based_peer_production&#34;&gt;Commons-based peer production&lt;/a&gt; is a Wikipedia entry licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nyu.edu/projects/nissenbaum/papers/jopp_235.pdf&#34;&gt;Commons-based Peer Production and Virtue&lt;/a&gt; published paper  by &lt;a href=&#34;http://benkler.org&#34;&gt;Yochai Benkler&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nyu.edu/projects/nissenbaum/&#34;&gt;Helen Nissenbaum&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;The Journal of Political Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;: Volume 14, Number 4, 2006, pp. 394–419.


&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-quest-taking-on-the-big-question&#34;&gt;Your Quest: Taking on the Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blah blah blah&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer by completing this CC Quest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the Opportunity of the Commons?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select a resource that you have created. Along with sharing the resource, share an evaluation of the opportunities and benefits that could come from sharing this resource with peers (reach, critique, collaborative peer production).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share a resource you own the copyright for and make a call for collaborative peer production/improvement of the material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find a resource and locate the copyright on the resource. Share the steps it would take to contact the copyright holder to use their work. This will help demonstrate an understanding of how much easier it is to use and share a CC licensed work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quest description &lt;a href=&#34;http://quests.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Complete this Quest&lt;/a&gt; (link to be added).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increase your CC Cred by &lt;a href=&#34;http://quests.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;doing additional quests&lt;/a&gt; (link to be added).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical vs Digital Commons</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/physical-digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/physical-digital/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a time in the new future in which all writing can be commercialized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-question&#34;&gt;The Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the magic of a new technology which can automatically capture and upload them to a website, every napkin doodle, every journal entry, and every love letter can be made available for sale as soon as you finish writing them. By means of improvements to operating systems like Windows, Mac, and Linux, all written documents like emails, homework assignments, and office memos can be automatically posted for sale on the site as soon as they are saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An upgrade to the technology might help users automatically offer all images they create for sale, from mobile phone photos to crayon drawings to watercolor paintings. Future versions of the technology might provide the same functionality for videos and sound recordings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/future-scanner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Technology Infographics Computer&#34; title=&#34;graphic of futuristic computer interface&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pixabay.com/en/technology-informatics-computers-298256/&#34;&gt;Technology-298256&lt;/a&gt; Pixabay image by &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixabay.com/en/users/andrelyra-201440/&#34;&gt;andreleya&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/&#34;&gt;CC0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now imagine that when this final version of the software is released, the national government requires all citizens to install it on all their devices, mandating the commercialization of every creative work that will ever be produced in the future, regardless of how trivial - or personal - it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a thousand things wrong with this scenario&lt;/strong&gt;. And while the technology sounds fantastic and distant, the legal foundation of this dystopian future is already in place. After joining the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Berne_Convention&#34;&gt;Berne Convention&lt;/a&gt;, most countries in the world now automatically apply copyright - the legal protections necessary to effectively commercialize a creative work - to each and every creative work the moment it is created, regardless of how personal or trivial it is. In this worldview that anticipates the commercialization of all creative works, a three year old child’s wobbly pencil drawing is protected to the same degree as Star Wars or Harry Potter. And this is not a hypothetical future scenario, it’s the actual state of affairs in the world today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation is utterly preposterous for many reasons, but one important reason is that many people create things with the goal of sharing them with others, like directions for purifying water after a natural disaster. What if a creator doesn’t want their work “protected” from copying and distribution, but wants it copied and shared as far and wide as technologically possible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Return to our imaginary scenario for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if, recognizing the public backlash, a second technology company created a tool that allowed a person to remove things from the website that commercialized all creative work? While it wouldn’t be able to prevent things from being placed on the site for sale automatically (as the law required), it would provide people with an easy - and legal - way to remove things from the site that they didn’t want to commercialize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to the real world, this is essentially what an open license does. Open licenses are easy to use legal tools - copyright licenses - that allow people to choose to share their work with others under a range of conditions. Rather than being forced to accept the default All Rights Reserved “protection” the law automatically forces on each and every creative work, a creator or author can choose to apply an open license license to their work, thereby allowing it to be copied and shared widely and legally. Many open licenses also grant permission to make changes and improvements to the work, like translating the document about purifying water into other languages. By applying an open license to their creation, an author places that work in a broader commons of creative works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/image-placeholder.png&#34; alt=&#34;lead image&#34; title=&#34;Lead Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://image.link&#34;&gt;Image Title&lt;/a&gt; site photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://person.link&#34;&gt;Person Name&lt;/a&gt;  is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons/org/licenselink&#34;&gt;CC-XX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dramatize problem open licensing is solving/addressing, how it is an alternative to copyright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Illustrate where open licensing exists on spectrum between public domain &amp;amp; copyright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain potentials, uses of open licensing, value of sharing as a default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze the reasons for open licensing in your context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define opportunities / benefits of collaborative peer production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate benefits of access to knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;opening-questions&#34;&gt;Opening Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should all writing, images, videos, sound recordings, and other creative works be automatically protected by copyright so they can be commercialized? Think of all the things you create every day - emails, photos, videos, and more. You may have authored a million or more creative works over your lifetime. Even if you are a creative professional and earn your livelihood by selling creative works, over 99.999% of what you have created has rightly gone uncommercialized. What might be the benefit of sharing some of these works with colleagues, peers, other organizations, or “the community”? How might your work be improved upon if you gave others permission to make improvements?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-it&#34;&gt;What is It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/image-placeholder.png&#34; alt=&#34;Nice image&#34; title=&#34;Nice Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://image.link&#34;&gt;Image Title&lt;/a&gt; site photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://person.link&#34;&gt;Person Name&lt;/a&gt;  is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons/org/licenselink&#34;&gt;CC-XX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-section&#34;&gt;Another Section&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we understand it, let’s talk a little bit about why it is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-section-1&#34;&gt;Another Section&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we understand it, let’s talk a little bit about why it is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-section-2&#34;&gt;Another Section&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we understand it, let’s talk a little bit about why it is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-to-explore&#34;&gt;More to Explore&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commons-based_peer_production&#34;&gt;Commons-based peer production&lt;/a&gt; is a Wikipedia entry licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nyu.edu/projects/nissenbaum/papers/jopp_235.pdf&#34;&gt;Commons-based Peer Production and Virtue&lt;/a&gt; published paper  by &lt;a href=&#34;http://benkler.org&#34;&gt;Yochai Benkler&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nyu.edu/projects/nissenbaum/&#34;&gt;Helen Nissenbaum&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;The Journal of Political Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;: Volume 14, Number 4, 2006, pp. 394–419.


&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-quest-taking-on-the-big-question&#34;&gt;Your Quest: Taking on the Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blah blah blah&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer by completing this CC Quest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the Opportunity of the Commons?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select a resource that you have created. Along with sharing the resource, share an evaluation of the opportunities and benefits that could come from sharing this resource with peers (reach, critique, collaborative peer production).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share a resource you own the copyright for and make a call for collaborative peer production/improvement of the material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find a resource and locate the copyright on the resource. Share the steps it would take to contact the copyright holder to use their work. This will help demonstrate an understanding of how much easier it is to use and share a CC licensed work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quest description &lt;a href=&#34;http://quests.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Complete this Quest&lt;/a&gt; (link to be added).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increase your CC Cred by &lt;a href=&#34;http://quests.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;doing additional quests&lt;/a&gt; (link to be added).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Creative Commons Organization</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/creative-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/commons/creative-commons/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;What if there was a means for creators to express willingness to share their knowledge and creative works? A simple and standardized way creators could use to give the public permission to use their work under certain conditions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-question&#34;&gt;The Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we combined that means with the power of the Internet and digital technology making it possible to share resources globally for the near marginal cost of $0?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/cc-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons&#34; title=&#34;Creative Commons&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/downloads/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Logo&lt;/a&gt; image by &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;  is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; does this very thing. Created as a US non-profit in 2002 and now with a global network, Creative Commons provides legal and technical infrastructure that helps creators legally share their knowledge and creativity to build a more equitable, accessible, and innovative world. Creative Commons licenses and digital tools, combined with the Internet, are driving new forms of development, growth and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/cc-staff.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Staff Berlin 17-Nov-2016&#34; title=&#34;Creative Commons Staff Berlin 17-Nov-2016&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;hhttps://drive.google.com/file/d/0B8IKbRz-8utNR253c2syOUFEV0E/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Staff Berlin 17-Nov-2016&lt;/a&gt; photo is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain why Creative Commons is necessary as an organization, mission &amp;amp; vision, goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate impact of Creative Commons, examples of program work, where it is used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify major initiatives, programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain, demonstrate Creative Commons resources and materials (including License Chooser, FAQ, and wiki)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe affiliate/community structures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain how to get involved, communicate with Creative Commons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-reflection-why-it-matters-to-you&#34;&gt;Personal Reflection / Why it Matters To You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you could freely access creative works what kinds of works would you seek? Books, music, film, cultural works? Research, education, data? What creative works do you or your organization have that have potential value to others? How might sharing those resources with others benefit you and the public?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;acquiring-essential-knowledge&#34;&gt;Acquiring Essential Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-to-creative-commons&#34;&gt;Introduction to Creative Commons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/cc-programs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Our Programs screen shot from Creative Commons web site&#34; title=&#34;Our Programs screen shot from Creative Commons web site&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/&#34;&gt;Our Programs screen shot from Creative Commons web site&lt;/a&gt; screenshot  is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a brief introduction to Creative Commons as an organization explore the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/&#34;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/share-your-work&#34;&gt;Share Your Work&lt;/a&gt; sections of Creative Commons web site. Watch the “Wanna Work Together” video on the Share Your Work page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/13590841&#34;&gt;https://vimeo.com/13590841&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;vision-mission-goals-program-areas&#34;&gt;Vision, Mission, Goals, Program Areas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn about Creative Commons vision, mission, goals, and program areas review the&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/program-areas/&#34;&gt;Program Areas&lt;/a&gt; section of the Creative Commons web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;global-use-and-impact&#34;&gt;Global use and impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/blog&#34;&gt;Creative Commons news blog&lt;/a&gt; to read stories from around the world of how people and organizations are using Creative Commons to generate personal and public good. The annual &lt;a href=&#34;https://stateof.creativecommons.org&#34;&gt;State of the Commons report&lt;/a&gt; provides data on size, growth, and vibrancy of the Commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-map/img/core/cc-state-commons.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2015 State of the Commons screen shot from Creative Commons web site&#34; title=&#34;2015 State of the Commons screen shot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stateof.creativecommons.org/2015&#34;&gt;2015 State of the Commons screen shot&lt;/a&gt; screenshot is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;creative-commons-tools-and-resources&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Tools and Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Familiarize yourself with the core tools Creative Commons provides including its &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/&#34;&gt;licenses and deeds&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/choose/&#34;&gt;license chooser&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/faq/&#34;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; provide answers to common questions and extensive support for best practice use of Creative Commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;creative-commons-headquarters-and-global-network&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Headquarters and Global Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out who the people running Creative Commons headquarters are from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/team/&#34;&gt;Team&lt;/a&gt; page. Creative Commons is a global movement with a network of practitioners and leaders around the world. Learn about the global community from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/global-affiliate-network/&#34;&gt;global affiliate network&lt;/a&gt; page and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.creativecommons.org/wiki/Category:CC_Affiliate_Locale&#34;&gt;identify representation from regions&lt;/a&gt; around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;communicating-with-creative-commons&#34;&gt;Communicating with Creative Commons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information on how to contact Creative Commons by phone or e-mail for general information is available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/contact/&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt; page. Creative Commons is active on social media and hosts numerous discussion forums and other channels of communication. If you join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack-signup.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Slack channel&lt;/a&gt; you’ll have direct, real time access to Creative Commons staff and colleagues. Find out the many ways you can connect and communicate with Creative Commons on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/get-involved/&#34;&gt;Get Involved&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;application-of-learning&#34;&gt;Application of Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CC Certificates aim to engage you in direct application of learning for personal and / or professional use. Toward that end the following learning activities aim to help you you use and apply basic knowledge in ways directly relevant to you. Learning activities are structured around 1. Creation of a personal learner toolkit. 2 Active participation in CC’s community, and 3. Applied practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learner-toolkit&#34;&gt;Learner Toolkit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select at least 2 or 3 resources directly relevant to your personal or work related CC needs from the Acquiring Basic Knowledge content and add them to your personal Creative Commons toolkit &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;link tba&lt;/a&gt;. Adding them to your toolkit makes it easy to find and use them when the need arises and makes it easy for you to pass on resources you consider important to others. Add comments explaining relevancy and importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-collaboration-appreciation-recognition-gratitude&#34;&gt;Community - Collaboration, Appreciation, Recognition, Gratitude&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the CC Certificate social forum post your answers to the personal reflection questions posed at the start of this learning unit. Identify and comment on posts from at least two others who have similar needs or ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign up for at least two means of connecting with Creative Commons such as following on Twitter, joining mailing lists of interest, subscribing to the Creative Commons newsletter, and joining the Creative Commons Slack channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Creative Commons news blog, Facebook page, Twitter stream and web pages identify at least two other people or organizations who are using Creative Commons in a similar way you or your organization do or want to do. Note these people or organizations in your Toolkit along with questions you might have for them in concerning advice or lessons learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;applied-practice&#34;&gt;Applied Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/share-your-work/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Share Your Work&lt;/a&gt; page lists a number of platforms like Wikipedia, Flickr, and Vimeo that provide their users with the option of licensing works with Creative Commons licenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the links to the platforms on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/share-your-work/&#34;&gt;Share Your Work&lt;/a&gt; page or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Search tool&lt;/a&gt; find and list in your Toolkit two or three resources that are representative of the kinds of creative works you said you would seek in Personal Reflections. Document the name of the resource, its url, identity of the creator, and Creative Commons license used. Make a comment beside each on how you might make use of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus applied practice:&lt;/strong&gt; Join Creative Commons global network. (note this activity will be relevant once the new global network strategy of CC is deployed.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>