<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Commons on CC Core Certification</title>
    <link>https://cogdog.github.io/cc-cert-hugo/commons/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Commons on CC Core Certification</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 15:17:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cogdog.github.io/cc-cert-hugo/commons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Significance of the Commons</title>
      <link>https://cogdog.github.io/cc-cert-hugo/commons/significance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 15:52:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cogdog.github.io/cc-cert-hugo/commons/significance/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;What do Wikipedia and medieval English pasture lands have in common? (Hint: the answer is right there in the question.) And why should you care?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-question&#34;&gt;The Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Wikipedia and medieval English pasture lands are examples of a commons. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bollier.org/commons-short-and-sweet&#34;&gt;As economist David Bollier describes it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a commons arises whenever a given community decides it wishes to manage a resource in a collective manner, with special regard for equitable access, use and sustainability”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commons are everywhere - from modern web communities to ancient agrarian communities - and understanding what they are and how they function is key to understanding the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably participate in one or more commons yourself - and by the time you finish this module you’ll be able to recognize a commons you are part of, describe what makes it a commons, and identify potential threats to the sustainability of your commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/creativecommons/cc-cert-core/blob/master/images/commons/pasture-wikipedia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;quot;English Pasture and Wikipedia logo&#34; title=&#34;English Pasture and Wikipedia logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Composite of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Plan_mediaeval_manor.jpg&#34;&gt;Fictional Medieval Manor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; dervivative Wikimedia Commons image by William R. Shepherd (1923) is shared into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/public_domain&#34;&gt;Public Domain&lt;/a&gt; and  &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Wikipedia_Logo_1.0.png&#34;&gt;Wikipedia Logo 1.0&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;  Wikimedia Commons image by &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/User:Nohat&#34;&gt;Nohat&lt;/a&gt;  licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define the commons and its historical significance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe historical and ongoing enclosure of the commons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide examples of common resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe culture as a form of commons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;opening-questions&#34;&gt;Opening Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What commons are you a part of? Can you think of a group you belong to that collectively manages a resource in order to make sure that everyone will have ongoing access to the resource? What do you contribute to your commons?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-commons-and-why-is-it-important&#34;&gt;What is a commons, and why is it important?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a brief introduction to the idea of a commons, watch these short videos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=41Dr8Te1OwE&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=41Dr8Te1OwE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=41Dr8Te1OwE&#34;&gt;Define the Commons&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChz4DMZKHYnAPVEjXduVFIA&#34;&gt;Remix The Commons&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7bQiBcd7mBc&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7bQiBcd7mBc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7bQiBcd7mBc&#34;&gt;How Does the Commons Work?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0Gw_ZWRG2eY_hPkAL7eNZg&#34;&gt;The Next System Project&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then read &lt;a href=&#34;http://bollier.org/commons-short-and-sweet&#34;&gt;The Commons, Short and Sweet&lt;/a&gt;  by &lt;a href=&#34;http://bollier.org/&#34;&gt;David Bollier&lt;/a&gt; for more detail about how commons work and why they are important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enclosure-of-the-commons&#34;&gt;Enclosure of the Commons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many historic commons ended in enclosure, and enclosure continues to be the single largest threat to modern commons. For a review of historical enclosures of physical commons and modern attempts to enclose the commons of ideas and culture, read The Second Enclosure Movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-enclosure&#34;&gt;What is Enclosure?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/creativecommons/cc-cert-core/blob/master/images/commons/hedge-enclosure-boundary.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enclosure Boundary&#34; title=&#34;photo of Enclosure Boundary&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geograph.org.uk/photo/1715089&#34;&gt;NZ0314 : Decaying hedge&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geograph.org.uk/profile/34816&#34;&gt;Andy Waddington&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt; / cropped from original&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many historic commons ended in enclosure, and enclosure continues to be the single largest threat to modern commons. For a review of historical enclosures of physical commons and modern attempts to enclose the commons of ideas and culture, read &lt;a href=&#34;http://boyle.yupnet.org/chapter-3-second-enclosure-movement/&#34;&gt;The Second Enclosure Movement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;successfully-managing-a-commons&#34;&gt;Successfully Managing a Commons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes a lot of effort to sustain a thriving commons. Read Nobel Prize-winning commons scholar Elinor Ostrom&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onthecommons.org/magazine/elinor-ostroms-8-principles-managing-commmons&#34;&gt;8 Principles for Managing a Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;application-of-learning&#34;&gt;Application of Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learner-toolkit&#34;&gt;Learner Toolkit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select two or three resources directly relevant to your personal or work-related CC needs from the Acquiring Essential Knowledge content and add them to your personal Creative Commons toolkit. Adding them to your toolkit makes them easy to find and use when the need arises, and makes it easy for you to pass on resources you consider important to others. Annotate the resources with notes explaining why they are relevant and important for you and your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-collaboration-appreciation-recognition-gratitude&#34;&gt;Community - Collaboration, Appreciation, Recognition, Gratitude&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identify a commons you participate in - think about the nature of the resources shared in the commons, some of the people who participate in the commons, and some of the community’s norms about how to create, manage, and sustain the resources in the commons. How do you benefit from your participation in that commons? Express your gratitude or appreciation to others who participate in that commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;applied-practice&#34;&gt;Applied Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete the following activity in the Quest Bank:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://quests.creativecommons.org/assignments/ostroms-eight-principles&#34;&gt;Give an Example of One of Ostrom’s Eight Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/cc-by-sa-88x31.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license&#34; title=&#34;CC BY-SA&#34; /&gt;
Licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license (CC BY-SA) version 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except where otherwise noted, this content is published under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA license&lt;/a&gt;, which means that you can copy, redistribute, remix, transform and build upon the content for any purpose even commercially as long as you give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made. If you remix, transform, or build upon the material, you must distribute your contributions under the same license as the original.
License details: &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creative Commons Certificates have been created with the kind support of &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imls.gov/&#34;&gt;Institute of Museum and Library Services&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gatesfoundation.org/&#34;&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Commons Opportunity</title>
      <link>https://cogdog.github.io/cc-cert-hugo/commons/opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 15:52:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cogdog.github.io/cc-cert-hugo/commons/opportunity/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world that anticipates the commercialization of all creative works - a world in which a three year old child’s wobbly crayon drawing would be protected to the same degree as Star Wars or Harry Potter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-question&#34;&gt;The Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After joining the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berne_Convention&#34;&gt;Berne Convention&lt;/a&gt; most countries in the world now automatically apply copyright - the legal protections necessary to effectively commercialize a creative work - to each and every  work the moment it is created. All creations are copyrighted, regardless of how personal or public they are. This is not a hypothetical future you have to imagine, it’s the actual state of affairs in the world today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/commons/copyright-iain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Copyright Iain&#34; title=&#34;Copyright Iain&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/iain/4804390638/&#34;&gt;Copyright Iain&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/iain/&#34;&gt;Iain Farrell&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/2.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-ND&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation is utterly preposterous for many reasons, but one important reason is that many people create things with the goal of sharing them with others. What if a creator doesn’t want their work “protected” from copying and distribution, but wants to see it copied and shared as far and wide as technologically possible?  For example, what if I’ve written a simple tutorial for purifying water after a natural disaster that I want everyone to have access to? When the law automatically copyrights my tutorial as if it were a major motion picture, how can I share it with others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what open licenses were created to do. Open licenses are easy to use legal tools - copyright licenses - that allow people to share their work with others under a range of conditions. Rather than being forced to accept the default All Rights Reserved “protection” the law automatically forces on each and every creative work, a creator or author can choose to apply an open license license to their work. This allows the work to be copied and shared widely and legally. Many open licenses also grant permission to make changes and improvements to the work, like translating the tutorial about purifying water into other languages. By applying an open license to their creation, an author places that work within a broader commons of creative works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dramatize problem open licensing is solving/addressing, how it is an alternative to copyright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Illustrate where open licensing exists on spectrum between public domain &amp;amp; copyright&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain potentials, uses of open licensing, value of sharing as a default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze the reasons for open licensing in your context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define opportunities / benefits of collaborative peer production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-reflection-why-it-matters-to-you&#34;&gt;Personal Reflection / Why It Matters to You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should all writing, images, videos, sound recordings, and other creative works be automatically protected by copyright? Think of all the things you create every day - emails, photos, videos, and more. You may have authored a million or more creative works over your lifetime. Even if you are a creative professional and earn your livelihood by selling creative works, over 99.999% of what you have created has rightly gone uncommercialized. What might be the benefit of sharing some of these works with others be? What might be the benefit of placing some of these resources in the commons?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;acquiring-essential-knowledge&#34;&gt;Acquiring Essential Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;creative-commons-as-an-alternative-to-all-rights-reserved&#34;&gt;Creative Commons as an Alternative to All Rights Reserved&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional approaches to copyright reserve all the rights associated with a work - including the rights to copy, alter, and distribute a work - for the copyright holder exclusively. Creative Commons enables a “some rights reserved” approach, allowing authors and creators to give others permission to engage in these activities under certain conditions as explained in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://iptla.byu.edu/courses/copyright_crash_course_for_teachers/open_licensing&#34;&gt;BYU Crash Course on Open Licensing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-spectrum-between-all-rights-reserved-and-the-public-domain&#34;&gt;The Spectrum Between All Rights Reserved and the Public Domain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creative Commons licenses exist along a continuum from the public domain (no rights reserved) to traditional copyright (all rights reserved) as illustrated below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/commons/cc-license-spectrum.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative commons license spectrum&#34; title=&#34;Creative commons license spectrum&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Creative_commons_license_spectrum.svg&#34;&gt;Creative commons license spectrum&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;CC BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-benefits-of-sharing&#34;&gt;The Benefits of Sharing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would anyone want to share the creations in which they’ve invested so much time and effort? Ryan Merkley, CEO of Creative Commons, explains many of the reasons in a short video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/151666798&#34;&gt;https://vimeo.com/151666798&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/151666798&#34;&gt;Creative Commons: Remix&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/creativecommonsvideos&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org.au&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Australia&lt;/a&gt; provides a more comprehensive list of of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org.au/content/Benefits_of_CC_08.pdf&#34;&gt;Benefits of Sharing Using Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-benefits-of-commons-based-peer-production&#34;&gt;The Benefits of Commons-based Peer Production&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commons-based_peer_production&#34;&gt;Commons-based peer production&lt;/a&gt; is a new way of producing creative and other works. In commons-based peer production, large numbers of people voluntarily self-organize to produce and provide ongoing stewardship of resources that are made broadly available. Commons-based peer production differs from traditional production models which are typically based on centralized planning and management, paid employees, and restricted access to final products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;application-of-learning&#34;&gt;Application of Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learner-toolkit&#34;&gt;Learner Toolkit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select two or three resources directly relevant to your personal or work-related CC needs from the Acquiring Essential Knowledge content and add them to your personal Creative Commons toolkit. Adding them to your toolkit makes them easy to find and use when the need arises, and makes it easy for you to pass on resources you consider important to others. Annotate the resources with notes explaining why they are relevant and important for you and your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-collaboration-appreciation-recognition-gratitude&#34;&gt;Community - Collaboration, Appreciation, Recognition, Gratitude&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post a story about how you benefited from someone who chose to share their creative works under a Creative Commons license in the CC Certificate social forum. Alternatively, share a description of (and link to, if applicable) a community that engages in commons-based peer production that others might not be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;applied-practice&#34;&gt;Applied Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete the following activity in the Quest Bank:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://quests.creativecommons.org/assignments/how-do-we-benefit&#34;&gt;How Do We Benefit? Let Me Count the Ways&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/cc-by-sa-88x31.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license&#34; title=&#34;CC BY-SA&#34; /&gt;
Licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license (CC BY-SA) version 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except where otherwise noted, this content is published under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA license&lt;/a&gt;, which means that you can copy, redistribute, remix, transform and build upon the content for any purpose even commercially as long as you give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made. If you remix, transform, or build upon the material, you must distribute your contributions under the same license as the original.
License details: &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creative Commons Certificates have been created with the kind support of &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imls.gov/&#34;&gt;Institute of Museum and Library Services&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gatesfoundation.org/&#34;&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical vs Digital Commons</title>
      <link>https://cogdog.github.io/cc-cert-hugo/commons/physical-digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 15:52:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cogdog.github.io/cc-cert-hugo/commons/physical-digital/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world in which someone has invented a machine that can produce perfect copies of any food item&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-question&#34;&gt;The Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you have to do is put in a single bowl of rice, or slice of pizza, or an apple, or a piece of cake, and the machine can make an infinite number of perfect copies for anyone who asks. And it can make those copies instantaneously. And for free. What would that world be like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet is exactly this kind of machine. All you have to do is upload a bit of writing, or an image, or a video - anything that can be represented and stored as bits - and the machine can  make an infinite number of perfect copies for anyone who asks. And it can make those copies instantaneously. And for free. And send them anywhere around the world at the speed of light. What is our world currently like? What &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; it be like if we leveraged this technology to its potential?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/commons/commons-copy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Copy Notices&#34; title=&#34;image of copy notices&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/unkle_cheese/828876896/&#34;&gt;Copy Notices&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/unkle_cheese/&#34;&gt;Jimmy Jim Jim Shabadoo&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide examples of physical and digital commons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare scarce (physical) vs. non-scarce (digital) resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain non-rivalrous goods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-reflection-why-it-matters-to-you&#34;&gt;Personal Reflection / Why it Matters to You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do we have the internet - perhaps the perfect machine for the free and open sharing of content - but not a copy machine for food? What are some of the differences between physical things like food and digital things like videos and web pages? How do these differences change the way you engage in commons centered on digital resources?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;acquiring-essential-knowledge&#34;&gt;Acquiring Essential Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;physical-and-digital-commons&#34;&gt;Physical and Digital Commons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/commons/digital-analog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Digital and Analog&#34; title=&#34;Digital vs Analog image, crayons on a tablet device&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/derekbruff/6134574629&#34;&gt;Digital Versus Analog&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;  by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/derekbruff/&#34;&gt;Derek Bruff&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY-NC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some significant differences between physical and digital commons. The brief video &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gJWbVt2Nc-I&#34;&gt;Why Open Education Matters&lt;/a&gt; provides a high-level overview of these differences in the context of education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gJWbVt2Nc-I&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gJWbVt2Nc-I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gJWbVt2Nc-I&#34;&gt;Why Open Education Matters&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCFiCJVgJzpWxoYnGjs752EQ&#34;&gt;David Blake&lt;/a&gt; licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more detail on the differences between physical and digital commons, we have to look more closely at the nature of the resources around which these commons are organized. To do this with clarity, we’ll need to employ some concepts from introductory economics. First, we need to understand Rivalry and Excludability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A resource is said to be rivalrous when one person’s use of the resource interferes with another person’s use of the resource. For example, if you eat a sandwich, I can’t eat the sandwich - this makes the sandwich a rivalrous resource. By contrast, if you watch a YouTube video that doesn’t prevent me (or a million other people) from watching that same video at the same time - this makes the video is a nonrivalrous resource. Read more about &lt;a href=&#34;https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Rivalry_(economics)&#34;&gt;Rivalry&lt;/a&gt; from Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A resource is said to be excludable if people can be prevented from accessing it. For example, when a television show is broadcast over the air it is a nonexcludable resource because there is no way to prevent an individual with a television from watching it. By contrast, when the same television show is broadcast by satellite it is encrypted so that only people who have the right equipment and a current subscription can watch it, making the show broadcast by satellite an excludable resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can build a table of rivalrous, nonrivalrous, excludable, and nonexcludable resources like the following one from Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Excludable&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Non-excludable&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rivalrous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Private_good&#34;&gt;Private goods&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; food, clothing, cars, parking spaces&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common-pool_resource&#34;&gt;Common-pool resources&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; fish stocks, timber, coal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonrivalrous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Club_good&#34;&gt;Club goods&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; cinemas, private parks, satellite television&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_good&#34;&gt;Public goods&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; free-to-air television, air, national defense&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take some time to explore the articles on Common-pool resources and Public goods linked in the table above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you understand these concepts, you will see that physical commons form around &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common-pool_resource&#34;&gt;common-pool resources&lt;/a&gt; and digital commons form around &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_good&#34;&gt;public goods&lt;/a&gt;. The difference between rivalrous resources and nonrivalrous resources lies at the heart of the difference between physical and digital commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;application-of-learning&#34;&gt;Application of Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learner-toolkit&#34;&gt;Learner Toolkit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select two or three resources directly relevant to your personal or work-related CC needs from the Acquiring Essential Knowledge content and add them to your personal Creative Commons toolkit. Adding them to your toolkit makes them easy to find and use when the need arises, and makes it easy for you to pass on resources you consider important to others. Annotate the resources with notes explaining why they are relevant and important for you and your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-collaboration-appreciation-recognition-gratitude&#34;&gt;Community - Collaboration, Appreciation, Recognition, Gratitude&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the CC Certificate social forum post some examples of private goods, club goods, common-pool resources, or public goods. Read some of the examples provided by others and see if you agree or disagree with how they have classified their examples and provide constructive, supportive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;applied-practice&#34;&gt;Applied Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete one or more following activities in the Quest Bank:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://quests.creativecommons.org/assignments/from-physical-to-digital&#34;&gt;From Physical to Digital&lt;/a&gt;  Analyze resources that were once only available physically but are now available in both physical and digital formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://quests.creativecommons.org/assignments/aspects-of-digital-vs-digital-sharing/&#34;&gt;Aspects of Physical and Digital Sharing&lt;/a&gt; What are the differences and related issues of sharing a physical object (like a book, recorded music, or a piece of art) versus digital versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/cc-by-sa-88x31.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license&#34; title=&#34;CC BY-SA&#34; /&gt;
Licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license (CC BY-SA) version 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except where otherwise noted, this content is published under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA license&lt;/a&gt;, which means that you can copy, redistribute, remix, transform and build upon the content for any purpose even commercially as long as you give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made. If you remix, transform, or build upon the material, you must distribute your contributions under the same license as the original.
License details: &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creative Commons Certificates have been created with the kind support of &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imls.gov/&#34;&gt;Institute of Museum and Library Services&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gatesfoundation.org/&#34;&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CC as an Organization in the Commons</title>
      <link>https://cogdog.github.io/cc-cert-hugo/commons/creative-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 15:53:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cogdog.github.io/cc-cert-hugo/commons/creative-commons/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;What if there was a means for creators to express willingness to share their knowledge and creative works? A simple and standardized way creators could use to give the public permission to use their work under certain conditions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-question&#34;&gt;The Big Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we combined that means with the power of the Internet and digital technology making it possible to share resources globally for the near marginal cost of $0?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/commons/cc-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons&#34; title=&#34;Creative Commons&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/downloads/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Logo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; does this very thing. Created as a US non-profit in 2002 and now with a global network, Creative Commons provides legal and technical infrastructure that helps creators legally share their knowledge and creativity to build a more equitable, accessible, and innovative world. Creative Commons licenses and digital tools, combined with the Internet, are driving new forms of development, growth and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/commons/cc-staff.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Staff Berlin 17-Nov-2016&#34; title=&#34;Creative Commons Staff Berlin 17-Nov-2016&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B8IKbRz-8utNR253c2syOUFEV0E/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Staff Berlin 17-Nov-2016&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; photo is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain why Creative Commons is necessary as an organization, mission &amp;amp; vision, goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate impact of Creative Commons, examples of program work, where it is used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify major initiatives, programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain, demonstrate Creative Commons resources and materials (including License Chooser, FAQ, and wiki)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe affiliate/community structures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain how to get involved, communicate with Creative Commons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-reflection-why-it-matters-to-you&#34;&gt;Personal Reflection / Why it Matters To You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you could freely access creative works what kinds of works would you seek? Books, music, film, cultural works? Research, education, data? What creative works do you or your organization have that have potential value to others? How might sharing those resources with others benefit you and the public?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;acquiring-essential-knowledge&#34;&gt;Acquiring Essential Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-to-creative-commons&#34;&gt;Introduction to Creative Commons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/commons/cc-programs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Our Programs screen shot from Creative Commons web site&#34; title=&#34;Our Programs screen shot from Creative Commons web site&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/&#34;&gt;Our Programs screen shot from Creative Commons web site&lt;/a&gt; screenshot  is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a brief introduction to Creative Commons as an organization explore the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/&#34;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/share-your-work&#34;&gt;Share Your Work&lt;/a&gt; sections of Creative Commons web site. Watch the “Wanna Work Together” video on the Share Your Work page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/13590841&#34;&gt;https://vimeo.com/13590841&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;vision-mission-goals-program-areas&#34;&gt;Vision, Mission, Goals, Program Areas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn about Creative Commons vision, mission, goals, and program areas review the&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/program-areas/&#34;&gt;Program Areas&lt;/a&gt; section of the Creative Commons web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;global-use-and-impact&#34;&gt;Global use and impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/blog&#34;&gt;Creative Commons news blog&lt;/a&gt; to read stories from around the world of how people and organizations are using Creative Commons to generate personal and public good. The annual &lt;a href=&#34;https://stateof.creativecommons.org&#34;&gt;State of the Commons report&lt;/a&gt; provides data on size, growth, and vibrancy of the Commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/commons/cc-state-commons.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2015 State of the Commons screen shot from Creative Commons web site&#34; title=&#34;2015 State of the Commons screen shot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stateof.creativecommons.org/2015&#34;&gt;2015 State of the Commons screen shot&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; screenshot is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC-BY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;creative-commons-tools-and-resources&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Tools and Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Familiarize yourself with the core tools Creative Commons provides including its &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/&#34;&gt;licenses and deeds&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/choose/&#34;&gt;license chooser&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/faq/&#34;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; provide answers to common questions and extensive support for best practice use of Creative Commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;creative-commons-headquarters-and-global-network&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Headquarters and Global Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out who the people running Creative Commons headquarters are from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/team/&#34;&gt;Team&lt;/a&gt; page. Creative Commons is a global movement with a network of practitioners and leaders around the world. Learn about the global community from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/global-affiliate-network/&#34;&gt;global affiliate network&lt;/a&gt; page and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.creativecommons.org/wiki/Category:CC_Affiliate_Locale&#34;&gt;identify representation from regions&lt;/a&gt; around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;communicating-with-creative-commons&#34;&gt;Communicating with Creative Commons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information on how to contact Creative Commons by phone or e-mail for general information is available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/contact/&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt; page. Creative Commons is active on social media and hosts numerous discussion forums and other channels of communication. If you join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack-signup.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Slack channel&lt;/a&gt; you’ll have direct, real time access to Creative Commons staff and colleagues. Find out the many ways you can connect and communicate with Creative Commons on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/about/get-involved/&#34;&gt;Get Involved&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;application-of-learning&#34;&gt;Application of Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CC Certificates aim to engage you in direct application of learning for personal and / or professional use. Toward that end the following learning activities aim to help you you use and apply basic knowledge in ways directly relevant to you. Learning activities are structured around 1. Creation of a personal learner toolkit. 2 Active participation in CC’s community, and 3. Applied practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learner-toolkit&#34;&gt;Learner Toolkit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select at least 2 or 3 resources directly relevant to your personal or work related CC needs from the Acquiring Basic Knowledge content and add them to your personal Creative Commons toolkit. Adding them to your toolkit makes it easy to find and use them when the need arises and makes it easy for you to pass on resources you consider important to others. Add comments explaining relevancy and importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-collaboration-appreciation-recognition-gratitude&#34;&gt;Community - Collaboration, Appreciation, Recognition, Gratitude&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the CC Certificate social forum post your answers to the personal reflection questions posed at the start of this learning unit. Identify and comment on posts from at least two others who have similar needs or ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign up for at least two means of connecting with Creative Commons such as following on Twitter, joining mailing lists of interest, subscribing to the Creative Commons newsletter, and joining the Creative Commons Slack channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/blog/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons news blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/creativecommons&#34;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/creativecommons&#34;&gt;Twitter stream&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;web pages&lt;/a&gt; identify at least two other people or organizations who are using Creative Commons in a similar way you or your organization do or want to do. Note these people or organizations in your Toolkit along with questions you might have for them in concerning advice or lessons learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;applied-practice&#34;&gt;Applied Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/share-your-work/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Share Your Work&lt;/a&gt; page lists a number of platforms like Wikipedia, Flickr, and Vimeo that provide their users with the option of licensing works with Creative Commons licenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the links to the platforms on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/share-your-work/&#34;&gt;Share Your Work&lt;/a&gt; page or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Search tool&lt;/a&gt; find and list in your Toolkit two or three resources that are representative of the kinds of creative works you said you would seek in Personal Reflections. Document the name of the resource, its url, identity of the creator, and Creative Commons license used. Make a comment beside each on how you might make use of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete the following activity in the Quest Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://quests.creativecommons.org/assignments/explain-what-creative-commons-is&#34;&gt;Explain What Creative Commons Is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus applied practice:&lt;/strong&gt; Join Creative Commons global network. (note this activity will be relevant once the new global network strategy of CC is deployed.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://creativecommons.github.io/cc-cert-core/images/cc-by-sa-88x31.png&#34; alt=&#34;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license&#34; title=&#34;CC BY-SA&#34; /&gt;
Licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license (CC BY-SA) version 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except where otherwise noted, this content is published under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA license&lt;/a&gt;, which means that you can copy, redistribute, remix, transform and build upon the content for any purpose even commercially as long as you give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made. If you remix, transform, or build upon the material, you must distribute your contributions under the same license as the original.
License details: &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creative Commons Certificates have been created with the kind support of &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imls.gov/&#34;&gt;Institute of Museum and Library Services&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gatesfoundation.org/&#34;&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>